<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ពាក្យបញ្ជាមូលដ្ឋាន on KOOMPI OS</title>
    <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ពាក្យបញ្ជាមូលដ្ឋាន on KOOMPI OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>kh-kh</language>
    <copyright>រក្សាសិទ្ធិដោយ © [គម្ពីរ](https://koompi.com/) ២០២០</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install/Remove</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/install-and-remove/install_remove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/install-and-remove/install_remove/</guid>
      <description>On Open-source software most applications are installed through Aur that contain app package.So, Here are the details for installing and removing packages details.
  Installing Packages Follow the following command to install a signal package including the dependencies:
 pi -S &amp;lt;Package name&amp;gt; or pi -i &amp;lt;Package name&amp;gt; For the list of packages installation:
 pi -S &amp;lt;Package name1 Package name2 ...&amp;gt;  Installing Package Group Some packages belong to a group of packages that simultaneously call installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users/Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/users-and-groups/users_groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/users-and-groups/users_groups/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Root Info</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/root/root/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/root/root/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cache Info</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/cache/cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/cache/cache/</guid>
      <description>Pi stores its downloaded packages in /var/cache/pacman/pkg/ and does not remove the old or uninstalled versions automatically. This has some advantages:
 It allows to downgrade a package without the need to retrieve the previous version through other means, such as the Arch Linux Archive. A package that has been uninstalled can easily be reinstalled directly from the cache folder, not requiring a new download from the repository.  However, it is necessary to deliberately clean up the cache periodically to prevent the folder to grow indefinitely in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Info</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/github/git_command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/github/git_command/</guid>
      <description>This module is a guide for details and usage of GitHub. If you are a newbie especially coding beginners and get to know what it is.
Install git We can start to install git by running a command in Konsole:
pi -S git  Make sure you have already run the command pi -Syu to update your system.
  Clone an existing repository If you want to clone your existing repository or you clone other people&amp;rsquo;s repository, you run the command below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link/Unlink</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/link/link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/link/link/</guid>
      <description>To make links between files you need to use ln command. A symbolic link (also known as a soft link or symlink) consists of a special type of file that serves as a reference to another file or directory.
ln is a command-line utility for creating links between files.By default, the ln command creates hard links. To create a symbolic link, use the -s (--symbolic) option.
There are two types of links in Linux/UNIX systems:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Info</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/network/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/network/network/</guid>
      <description>Network is included by two or more computers that are linked to share resources (such as printers and CDs), exchange files, or allow electronic communications. NetworkManager is the configuration of the network on the interfaces, which is the software utility that aims to simplify the use of computer networks.
  Check the connection To ensure about the network connection, go through the following conditions below:
 Your network interface is listed and enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Management</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/power-management/power_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/power-management/power_management/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching/History</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/system-manager/system_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/system-manager/system_manager/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/other/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/kh/basic/other/others/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!! **Noted**: If the **pi** database files are corrupted, and there is no backup file available, there exists some hope of rebuilding the pi database. {.is-info} # Reinstalling all packages To reinstall all native packages, use: ```shell pi -Qqn | pi -S - ``` # Querying Package Database ```shell $ pi -Q #queries the local package database $ pi -s #sync database $ pi -F #files database ``` For more options about querying: ```shell $ pi -Q --help ``` Options: ```shell -b, --dbpath  # set an alternate database location -c, --changelog # view the changelog of a package -d, --deps # list packages installed as dependencies [filter] -e, --explicit # list packages explicitly installed [filter] -g, --groups # view all members of a package group -i, --info # view package information (-ii for backup files) -k, --check # check that package files exist (-kk for file properties) -l, --list # list the files owned by the queried package -m, --foreign # list installed packages not found in sync db(s) [filter] -n, --native # list installed packages only found in sync db(s) [filter] -o, --owns  # query the package that owns  -p, --file  # query a package file instead of the database -q, --quiet # show less information for query and search -r, --root  # set an alternate installation root -s, --search  # search locally-installed packages for matching strings -t, --unrequired # list packages not (optionally) required by any package (-tt to ignore optdepends) [filter] -u, --upgrades # list outdated packages [filter] -v, --verbose # be verbose --arch  # set an alternate architecture --cachedir  # set an alternate package cache location --color  # colorize the output --config  # set an alternate configuration file --confirm # always ask for confirmation --debug # display debug messages --disable-download-timeout # use relaxed timeouts for download --gpgdir  # set an alternate home directory for GnuPG --hookdir  # set an alternate hook location --logfile  # set an alternate log file --noconfirm # do not ask for any confirmation --sysroot # operate on a mounted guest system (root-only) ```  **Warning**: Sometimes, -s&#39;s builtin ERE (Extended Regular Expressions) can cause a lot of unwanted results, so it has to be limited to match the package name only; not the description nor any other field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>