<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KOOMPI OS</title>
    <link>https://www.koompi.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on KOOMPI OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright by  © KOOMPI 2020 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.koompi.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/browser/browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/browser/browser/</guid>
      <description>A web browser, or simply &amp;ldquo;browser,&amp;rdquo; is a software application for accessing information on the World Wide Web. When a user requests a web page from a particular website, the web browser retrieves the necessary content from a web server and then displays the page on the screen.
The most popular browsers have a number of features in common. They allow users to set bookmarks and browse in a private mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Editing Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/code-editors/code_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/code-editors/code_editor/</guid>
      <description>Code editors are a small piece of software like a text editor. The only difference is code editors have special functionalities than text editors.
According to the language used to code, the code editors highlight special keywords, give suggestions to some extent, automatic indentation features, and sometimes it has an integrated terminal as well.
 This document providesa completed details of the list of available coding apps that could be install in KOOMPI OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflicted FAQs</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/faqs/conflicts_faqs/conflicts_faqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/faqs/conflicts_faqs/conflicts_faqs/</guid>
      <description>Conflicting with p11-kit-trust ?    Meanwhile, you are updating the OS and you are facing this kind of conflicting.
Sample of output you are commonly facing:
problem: nss: /usr/lib/p11-kit-trust.so exists in filesystem lib32-nss: /usr/lib32/p11-kit-trust.so exists in filesystem As you can notice that p11-kit-trust.so, you need to overwrite it.
sudo pacman -Syu --overwrite /usr/lib\*/p11-kit-trust.so    Error with Modprobe and Vboxdrv ?    It appears that I have problem with modprobe vboxdrv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/converter/converter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/converter/converter/</guid>
      <description>Converter is the app that helps the user for converting text file formats, documents, media file format (image, audio, and even video).
In this article, we are going to introduce you guys the converting applications that mostly use in the KOOMPI OS.
 Chart list below is providing the Name and commands:
   Converter Names Installing Commands     Audio Convert pi -S audio-convert    HandBrake pi -S handbrake    SoundConverter pi -S soundconverter    Soundkonverter pi -S soundkonverter      Audio Convert Audio Convert is a script that converts between WAV, Ogg, MP3, MPC, FLAC, APE, AAC, and WMA files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/documentation/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/documentation/documentation/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the whole documentation is talking about the information which is related to document Apps that can be downloaded in this OS with the highly supported in system.
And we are going to recommen all of you to use which apps that is very suitable for your system and even your work.
If you have questions about the anything, you can check it here for the answers. If you want to submit any new question you can sub up to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/downloader/downloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/downloader/downloader/</guid>
      <description>In here is where all information about the downloading applications.
A download manager is a software tool that manages to quickly downloading many types of files from the Internet and organize them as you see fit, which may be built into a Web browser, or usually more sophisticated, or even a stand-alone manager.
You can categorize each file as you download it, and then access all downloads right from the app&amp;rsquo;s main interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Files/Folders</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/flies-and-folders/flie-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/flies-and-folders/flie-folder/</guid>
      <description>This document is a guide for information related to Files and Folders. All the Command lines will be provided here with the explanation plus the example.
For more details of the instruction, see KOOMPI OS website articles or the various program section, both linked from this guide.
  Create File Knowing how to create a new file is an important skill for anyone using open-source regularly. You can create a new file either from the command line or from the desktop file manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/github/git_command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/github/git_command/</guid>
      <description>This module is a guide for details and usage of github. If you are a newbie especialy coding beginners and get to know what it is.
Install git We can start to install git by run a command in konsole:
pi -S git  Make sure you have already run command pi -Syu to update your system.
  Clone an existing repository If you want to clone your existing repository or you clone other people&amp;rsquo;s repository, you run command below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Editor Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/graphic-editor/graphic_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/graphic-editor/graphic_editor/</guid>
      <description>As we all know that graphic editor is one of the common apps for the demand of editing the images whether they are digital photographs, traditional photo-chemical photographs, or illustrations. So, Here is the document that describes and provides more info and an app for using.
Please, make sure you have already updated your system with this command &amp;ldquo;pi -Syu&amp;rdquo;.
  Chart list of Graphic Editors:
   Graphic Editor Names Installing Commands     Darktable pi -S darktable    Digikam pi -S digikam    GIMP pi -S gimp   Inkscape pi -S inkscape    Krita pi -S krita    Pinta pi -S pinta    Photoshop pix -i adope-photoshop-cc    RawTherapee pi -S rawtherapee      Darktable I let you store all the precious digital negatives in a database that you can, later on, develop raw images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/intermediate-command/intermediate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/intermediate-command/intermediate/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!! **Noted**: If the **pi** database files are corrupted, and there is no backup file available, there exists some hope of rebuilding the pi database. {.is-info} # Reinstalling all packages To reinstall all native packages, use: ```shell pi -Qqn | pi -S - ``` # Password Info Both **KOOMPI OS** and **Linux** operating systems use the `passwd` command to change the user password. The `passwd` is used to update a user’s authentication token (password) stored in `/etc/shadow file`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Player Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/music-platform/music_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/music-platform/music_platform/</guid>
      <description>Not many music platform or apps can be installed in open-source system. Music platform companies are focusing on mobile app. We recommend you guy to use mobile apps or on browser, but if you guy want to install in desktop. Here is some apps that we can install in open-source world.
This document is containing only apps that possibly to install in the OS, If you want to install other apps beside the infomation we are providing, it is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/network/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/network/network/</guid>
      <description>Network is included by two or more computers that are linked to share resources (such as printers and CDs), exchange files, or allow electronic communications. NetworkManager is the configuration of the network on the interfaces, which is the software utility that aims to simplify the use of computer networks.
Check the connection To ensure about the network connection, go through the following conditions below:
 Your network interface is listed and enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pix Release</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/release/pix-release/pix_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/release/pix-release/pix_release/</guid>
      <description>Pix sounds familiar to pi but it is quite different because it stands for pacman extended or extra which is supported by many more applications which Pi can’t do. So, Our team has been trying to creat this functional in case users want to install some apps which our OS officially support yet.
In this document, The details about what pix will be providing to the all users. First thing first, As pix is just relesed we have to install it by following the steps below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/printing/printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/printing/printing/</guid>
      <description>coming soon!!! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/recorder/recorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/recorder/recorder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</guid>
      <description>coming soon !!! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/media/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/media/media/</guid>
      <description>As the social media platform has been the most powerful application which not only for communication but also for gathering a lot of information around everywhere in the world. Even they have been developed by many different companies but still focus on one main point that makes the users stay connected.
So in this section, we are going to introduce many social platforms and a little details about them.
 Here is the list chart on the Media apps plus command to install them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/system-control/system_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/system-control/system_control/</guid>
      <description>Systemctl is init system and system manager that is widely becoming the new standard for opensource machines. While there are considerable opinions about whether systemd is an improvement over the traditional SysV init systems it is replacing, the majority of distributions plan to adopt it or have already done so.
Due to its heavy adoption, familiarizing yourself with systemd is well worth the trouble, as it will make administering servers considerably easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users/Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/users-and-groups/users-and-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/users-and-groups/users-and-groups/</guid>
      <description>coming soon!!! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Editor Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/video-editor/video_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/video-editor/video_editor/</guid>
      <description>As Window has widely used photo editor enterprise-level Photo management and editing software. So does KoompiOS which contain a large number of open-source industry professionals software.Down here are the avaible software you can install in the KOOMPI OS. And surprisingly all comes with a handful of features and tools to fulfill your image editing or painting or designing task.
 We are providing the list chart on the Video Editor with the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Player Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/video-player/video_player/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/video-player/video_player/</guid>
      <description>Since there have been video editors, there also have Video Players. They have been used as the platforms for playback the video or watching the video.
    Social Media Names Installing Command     VLC pi -S vlc   MPlayer pi -S mplayer   KMplayer pi -S kmplayer   MPV pi -S mpv      VLC VLC Media Player is one of the best and most popular Best Linux Software in the category of video players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Stack (LAMP)</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/lamp/lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/lamp/lamp/</guid>
      <description>A LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) stack is a common web stack used to prepare servers for hosting web content. This guide shows you how to install a LAMP stack an KOOMPI OS.
This guide is written for a non-root user. Commands that require elevated privileges are prefixed with sudo. If you’re not familiar with the sudo command, you can check our Users and Groups guide.
  In order to install lamp server, you need to run the command in terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/applications/others/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/applications/others/others/</guid>
      <description>Abiword Abiword is free word processing program similar to Microsoft® Word. It is suitable for a wide variety of word processing tasks.
How to install Abiword To install it run this command in terminal:
pi -S abiword  FonteForge FontForge is a font editor which supports many common font formats. FontForge is free software and is distributed under a mix of the GNU General Public License Version 3 and the 3-clause BSD license.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>