<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Basic Commands on KOOMPI OS</title>
    <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Basic Commands on KOOMPI OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright by  © KOOMPI 2020 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.koompi.org/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Files/Folders</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/flies-and-folders/flie-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/flies-and-folders/flie-folder/</guid>
      <description>This document is a guide for information related to Files and Folders. All the Command lines will be provided here with the explanation plus the example.
For more details of the instruction, see KOOMPI OS website articles or the various program section, both linked from this guide.
  Create File Knowing how to create a new file is an important skill for anyone using open-source regularly. You can create a new file either from the command line or from the desktop file manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/github/git_command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/github/git_command/</guid>
      <description>This module is a guide for details and usage of GitHub. If you are a newbie especially coding beginners and get to know what it is.
Install git We can start to install git by running a command in Konsole:
pi -S git  Make sure you have already run the command pi -Syu to update your system.
  Clone an existing repository If you want to clone your existing repository or you clone other people&amp;rsquo;s repository, you run the command below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/intermediate-command/intermediate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/intermediate-command/intermediate/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon!! **Noted**: If the **pi** database files are corrupted, and there is no backup file available, there exists some hope of rebuilding the pi database. {.is-info} # Reinstalling all packages To reinstall all native packages, use: ```shell pi -Qqn | pi -S - ``` # Password Info Both **KOOMPI OS** and **Linux** operating systems use the `passwd` command to change the user password. The `passwd` is used to update a user’s authentication token (password) stored in `/etc/shadow file`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/network/network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/network/network/</guid>
      <description>Network is included by two or more computers that are linked to share resources (such as printers and CDs), exchange files, or allow electronic communications. NetworkManager is the configuration of the network on the interfaces, which is the software utility that aims to simplify the use of computer networks.
Check the connection To ensure about the network connection, go through the following conditions below:
 Your network interface is listed and enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/printing/printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/printing/printing/</guid>
      <description>coming soon!!! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching/History</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/search-and-find/searchfind/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the commands and how you can quickly use it to locate files in your filesystem. Finding file is a powerful utility capable of locating files anywhere on your system including mounted drives and removable storage, processing regular expressions, and even running other commands on those files. Fortunately, only a few simple options are needed to provide most users with all the capability they need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/system-control/system_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/system-control/system_control/</guid>
      <description>Systemctl is init system and system manager that is widely becoming the new standard for opensource machines. While there are considerable opinions about whether systemd is an improvement over the traditional SysV init systems it is replacing, the majority of distributions plan to adopt it or have already done so.
Due to its heavy adoption, familiarizing yourself with systemd is well worth the trouble, as it will make administering servers considerably easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users/Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.koompi.org/basic/users-and-groups/users-and-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.koompi.org/basic/users-and-groups/users-and-groups/</guid>
      <description>coming soon!!! </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>