<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Applications Info on KOOMPI OS</title>
    <link>https://pionux.org/applications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Applications Info on KOOMPI OS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright by  © KOOMPI 2020 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pionux.org/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/browser/browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/browser/browser/</guid>
      <description>A web browser, or simply &amp;ldquo;browser,&amp;rdquo; is a software application for accessing information on the World Wide Web. When a user requests a web page from a particular website, the web browser retrieves the necessary content from a web server and then displays the page on the screen.
The most popular browsers have a number of features in common. They allow users to set bookmarks and browse in a private mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Editing Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/code-editors/code_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/code-editors/code_editor/</guid>
      <description>Code editors are a small piece of software like a text editor. The only difference is code editors have special functionalities than text editors.
According to the language used to code, the code editors highlight special keywords, give suggestions to some extent, automatic indentation features, and sometimes it has an integrated terminal as well.
 This document providesa completed details of the list of available coding apps that could be install in KOOMPI OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/converter/converter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/converter/converter/</guid>
      <description>Converter is the app that helps the user for converting text file formats, documents, media file format (image, audio, and even video).
In this article, we are going to introduce you guys the converting applications that mostly use in the KOOMPI OS.
Audio Convert Audio Convert is a script that converts between WAV, Ogg, MP3, MPC, FLAC, APE, AAC, and WMA files. It has an easy-to-use interface that makes it possible to fill in the tags for a few formats, copy the tags from input files into the new files, and choose the quality of compression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Document Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/documentation/documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/documentation/documentation/</guid>
      <description>In this part of the whole documentation is talking about the information which is related to document Apps that can be downloaded in this OS with the highly supported in system.
And we are going to recommen all of you to use which apps that is very suitable for your system and even your work.
If you have questions about the anything, you can check it here for the answers. If you want to submit any new question you can sub up to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/downloader/downloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/downloader/downloader/</guid>
      <description>In here is where all information about the downloading applications.
A download manager is a software tool that manages to quickly downloading many types of files from the Internet and organize them as you see fit, which may be built into a Web browser, or usually more sophisticated, or even a stand-alone manager.
You can categorize each file as you download it, and then access all downloads right from the app&amp;rsquo;s main interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Editor Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/graphic-editor/graphic_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/graphic-editor/graphic_editor/</guid>
      <description>As we all know that graphic editor is one of the common app for demand of editing the images wheather they are digital photographs, traditional photo-chemical photographs, or illustrations. So, Here is the document that describes and provides more info and app for using.
Please, make sure you have already updated your system with this command &amp;ldquo;pi -Syu&amp;quot;.
 Darktable I let you store all the precious digital negatives in a database that you can, later on, develop raw images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Player Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/music-platform/music_platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/music-platform/music_platform/</guid>
      <description>Not many music platform or apps can be installed in open-source system. Music platform companies are focusing on mobile app. We recommen you guy to use mobile apps or on browser, but if you guy want to install in desktop. Here is some apps that we can install in open-source world.
This document is containing only apps that possibly to install in the OS, If you want to install other apps beside the infomation we are providing, it is impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/recorder/recorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/recorder/recorder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/media/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/media/media/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Editor Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/video-editor/video_editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/video-editor/video_editor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Player Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/video-player/video_player/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/video-player/video_player/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Stack (LAMP)</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/lamp/lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/lamp/lamp/</guid>
      <description>A LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) stack is a common web stack used to prepare servers for hosting web content. This guide shows you how to install a LAMP stack an KOOMPI OS.
This guide is written for a non-root user. Commands that require elevated privileges are prefixed with sudo. If you’re not familiar with the sudo command, you can check our Users and Groups guide.
 In order to install lamp server, you need to run the command in terminal:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others Apps</title>
      <link>https://pionux.org/applications/others/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 11:02:05 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pionux.org/applications/others/others/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>